Title	TitleCN	Artist Name 作者名	Info	InfoCN	Description	DescriptionCN	
Are you coming to my house for dinner tonight?	你晚上来不来我家吃饭？	Guan Qi 观奇	21.5*15cm. Published on demand.	自出版	"It surprised me that these crimes of such a serious nature and centered around gender and sexuality are so prevalent in our daily lives and upbringing that so many stories can come out of a casual conversation between two (body) women. I thought I'd draw it, so I asked Strawman Fire for her opinion, and she said yes. I tried to visualize her experiences through her words and remembered some of the past along my own lines. When I finished the drawing, Strawman Fire brought her friends over, and she said she wanted to draw a small poster for the comic, which is the two postcards inside the bag."	我很惊讶于这些性质严重的、围绕性别和性的犯罪居然如此普遍地存在于我们的日常生活和成长经历中，以至于两个（身体）女性随便聊天就可以聊出这么多故事。想了想还是要画下来，于是征求了草人火的意见，她说好呀。我试着经由她的话想象她的经历，也沿着自己的线条想起了一些以前的事。画完了正好草人火带着朋友们来家里做客，她说要给这个漫画画个小海报，那就是袋子里面的两张明信片。	
Untitled (Bonnie's projection)	无题 (Bonnie的项目)	Bonnie Wong	"11*16 cm, 88p. First-self-published in size of 100."	印量/版数: 100/1，自出版	"A book of the past and the future. Bonnie’s Projection is a Riso-printed booklet created from founded materials such as old maps, vintage textbooks, scientific diagrams, collected printed matters, and archival documents from the National Archives in Richmond, London. The theme of this book looks into topics such as colonial history, collective memory and identity."	一本跟过去和未来有关的书。Bonnie’s Projection是一本以孔版印刷制作的书誌，取材自作者旅行期间和日常生活中收 藏的纸本材料，比如旧地图、中古教科书、地理和科学图鑑、以及从伦敦的英国国家档案馆收集的文件。透过改动客 观的资料，本书以图像去探讨如群体记忆、殖民歷史、身分认同等议题。	
Lonely Station Newspaper	站台光年报	仁科	"39*54 cm, 4p, 2023. First-published by Shinning Hair Publishing Studio in size of 10."	10/1，闪念毛毛出版社出版	"the Mosquito Incense Planet has burned out. RENKE released an EP, and the kid next door was moved to tears listening to it"	大危机，蚊香星球烧没了，RENKE发行EP， 隔壁小孩都听哭了。	
Four hundred and three apples & One hundred and sixty eight walnuts	403个苹果和168个核桃	Xiao Zhang 张晓	"21*14.8 cm, 592p, 2022. Published by Apple Department Store."	苹果百货⼤楼出版	"The hometown of the author of this book is the largest apple-producing region in China, and the time when the author's parents send him apples in the mail every year after the apple picking has become a temporary channel of connection and communication between parents and children. So the author took a photo of every apple he received in 2016 to preserve this connection."	本书作者家乡是中国最大的苹果产区，每年苹果采摘之后，作者父母给他邮寄苹果的时间成了亲子之间联系和交流的一条临时通道。所以作者给2016年收到的每个苹果都拍了一张照片，去保存这种联系。	
Bebepapa	悲悲爸爸	anusman 王烁	Published by 鼹书	鼹书出版	"Wang Shuo is an amateur cartoonist, cartoon critic, and the first person to study independent cartooning in China. After graduating from Tsinghua University, majoring in printmaking, he studied in France for five years and received a master's degree in cartooning from the Institut Européen d'Images in Angoulême, France, during which time he published Anusman's Silent Comics 1&2. After returning to China, he taught at the Central Academy of Fine Arts and received a doctorate degree, and authored the comic book textbook Comics Lesson: New Language of Comics."	王烁(anusman)是一名业余漫画家、漫画评论者、国内第一个研究独立漫画的人。清华大学美术学院版画专业毕业后赴法国留学五年，获法国安古兰欧洲图像学院漫画硕士，期间出版《anusman的无字漫画1&2》。回国后于中央美术学院教书，并获得博士学位，并著有漫画教材《漫画课：漫画新语》。	
zhèn	鸩	Lin Shu 林舒	"10.5*21 cm (unfolds into 40.5*21 cm), 70p, 2021. First-published by YanShu in size 300."	印量/版数: 300/1，鼹书出版	"This collection of photographs was taken in the locations of Mount Huangshan, Mount Tai, Mount Lushan, Mount Emei, Mount Wudang, Mount Huashan, as well as Zhangjiajie and Guilin. It is a free portrayal of China's most valuable and beautiful traditions in the artist's mind, taking the unchanging form of the mountains as the object of communication between ""self"" and the world of the past, and experiencing the ancient Chinese artist's feelings and understanding of the mountains in the process of photographing."	这组照片拍摄的地点来自黄山、泰山、庐山、峨眉山、武当山、华山，以及张家界和桂林。是艺术家心中对于中国最有价值最美好的传统的一次恣意描摹，将亘古不变的山的形态当作“我”与过去的世界沟通的对象，在拍摄过程中去体会中国古代艺术家对于山的情感和认识。	
Memorandum of Light	光明备忘录	Wang Wei 王炜	"14*22 cm, 132p, July 2022. First-published by 51 Personae."	51人出版	"Poet Wang Wei's latest collection, Memorandum of Light, includes his poems written in 2020-2021. Wang Wei's style of writing in terms of tone, theme, and thought, his understanding of the political condition of life, and his self-awareness-based trajectory through the history of world literature and thought are all presented in this collection of poems."	诗人王炜的最新诗集《光明备忘录》，收录其写于2020-2021年的诗。笔调、主题与思路方面的王炜式写作风格，对生命政治状况的理解，基于自我认知的对世界文学与思想史的洄溯，在这本诗集中均有呈现。	
Prickly Paper: Extra: The Story of Liu Sheng	刺纸 号外：刘胜的故事	Prickly Paper/Liu Sheng 刺纸/刘胜	"104 pages,19*32cm, 2021,self published"	104页，19*32cm，自出版	"In the spring of 2020, Prickly Paper launched a special issue called The Story of Liu Sheng. Liu Sheng is a delivery man, who often delivers packages to staff in our editorial team. fter scrolling through Liu's updates on his WeChat page, Yifei found that he makes a perfect narrator. Then he asked for Liu's permission to compile the contents he posted on the SNS platform and interviewed his friends and him."	2020 年春，《刺纸》发行了号外《刘胜的故事》。刘胜是在小洲工作的一位快递员，经常给编辑部成员投送快递，成为了编辑陈逸飞的微信好友。疫情期间，刘胜困于湖北仙桃老家而无法返回工作。在翻看刘胜朋友圈时，编辑发现他是一位很好的自述者，于是在征求了本人的意见后，对他的朋友圈进行采编，并邀请往期作者提交回应，制作了一本关于刘胜的特刊。	
Prickly Paper: No.1	刺纸春报 第一期	Prickly Paper 刺纸		/	"Prickly Paper is a handmade journal established in 2019. The editorial team positions it as a ""restroom literature,"" and its name ""刺纸"" sounds like the Cantonese pronunciation of ""toilet paper."" ""Prickly Paper was originally conceived during the exhibition project ""First Boundless Architecture Season Exhibition Plan, Third Unit: Yida Building Reconstruction Project"" at the Fei Art Museum in Guangzhou."	《刺纸》是一本创立于2019年的手工期刊。编辑部成员将其定位为一本“如厕读物”，其名“刺纸”也谐音粤语“厕纸”。《刺纸》最初诞生于广州扉美术馆的展览项目《第一回无界建筑季展览计划·第三单元：亿达大厦再建计划》。参展艺术家们可以在大厦中自由选择展出地点，欧飞鸿选择了厕所，想制作一本给都市白领阅读的厕所读物。《刺纸》的第一、二期就由此诞生了。《刺纸》编辑部成员没有采取常规的印厂印刷，而是使用了手工木刻加家庭打印的方式来实现一种另类表达，风格粗砺，兼有出版物和手工艺品双重属性。在内容创作方面，《刺纸》从不依赖专业的写作者，而是从普通人的日常表达中寻找创作灵感，并结合文字和图像两种不同的表达形式进行再创造。	
Prickly Paper：Sandy Bay 501	刺纸：沙湾501	Prickly Paper 刺纸		/	"Three years ago,a man drove his motorbike around the city at night and graffiti in the public place. He was careless in the operation and was thrown into the detention house for seven months. Now, He edits the documents, letters and sketches during that period prints them into a awesome handmade book called""Shawan No.501”."	一个男人驾着摩托车夜巡都市一路在公共场所乱涂乱画，最终操作不慎，被寻衅滋事投进看守所7个月。三年后，借由《刺纸》号外专刊，终得整理在期间保存下来的文件以及书信绘画，编辑印刷装订成一本劲爆手工书。	
Prickly Paper：Village News	刺纸村报	刺纸/甘妈妈饺子坊 Prickly Paper/Mama Gan's Dumpling Shop		/	The Village Paper: a light-weight newspaper that hopes to record the daily life of Xiaozhou Village from the perspective of different individuals. The first issue is an interview with the owner of a dumpling shop in the alleyway.	村报:希望以轻便的报纸记录不同个体视角下的小洲村日常。第一期是访谈巷子里的一家水饺店老板。	
Prickly Paper 5：Menstrual blood is not dirty	刺纸5：经血不脏	50 Co-Creators/Han Lilin Edits 50人共创/韩里林主编		/	"Menstruation is an everyday thing that is relevant to most people, yet an intimate and neglected personal experience that has lacked a wide dialogue.This time, we are calling for contributions through The Prickly Paper to discuss and write about topics related to menstruation with friends, and together we will try to change the private nature of menstruation into an interchangeable experience."	月经是与大部分人都有关的日常之事，但又是私密的被忽视的个人体验，一直缺乏广泛的对话。这次，我们通过《刺纸》征稿，与朋友们讨论、书写和月经有关的话题，一起试着改变月经的私密性质，调拨为可互通之经验。责编:韩里林、欧飞鸿 封面木刻:韩里林、许观奇、渣渣、海兔和伏特加、于婉莹	
Prickly Paper 6: Menopause	刺纸6：更年期	Prickly Paper/Li Ping 刺纸/李平		/	/	/	
àn: A Summer of Annamese Craftsmen and French Colonial Administrator H.J. Oger	[汗頁]——安南手藝人和法屬參辦奧格的同一個夏天	Initiated and desiend by 隐二，co-created by 李沐杰、朱琺、江垚、杨杭平、Ewbar、龙彦丞、yoyo、海冉、九个妖、毛晨雨、crisken、Strongman、Mog、隐二、苍间、张雷	"23*31*3 cm, 269p, 2023. First-published in size of 60 limited editions by Grilling Park."	「桂林公園」互促社出版	"This book is the result of a collection of woodcuts that Henri J. Oger, a lowly civil servant in French Indochina, initiated and produced 100 years ago in what was then Vietnam to observe and document the lives and labors of local laborers; 100 years later, the authors encountered this pioneering self-publishing album and created this book as an intertwined set of books that echoed the original in a clustered and ""interventionist remake. A hundred years later, the authors encountered this pioneering self-published collection of drawings and created a group reading and ""interventional remastering"" of the book that echoes the original."	100年前法属印度支那低等文官Henri J. Oger在当时的越南发起和制作了一套观察和记录当地劳动者生活劳作场景的木刻画集。100年后的我们邂逅了这套堪称自出版先驱的画册，在Oger的热情和那些古代越南的画师、刻工、印工的能量几乎泯然于历史之际，我们以集群共读并且“介入式重制”的方式共同创作了这套与原著交相呼应的书。秉承半手工小批量做书的原则，这次制作利用大量现成纸品物的挪用和改造，书的名字“汗頁”（发音暗）意在表达是具体的“身体感”让我们和100年前的做书人心灵共振、声气相通。	
51Tan	51摊	A Recorder 一位记录者	"156p, Oct 2021. First-published by 51 Personae & Li Junfeng @ Otter Culture"	51人 & 李俊峰@水獭文化出版	"51 Tan is an ongoing documentary. As one of the participants in the 51-person project at the 11th Shanghai Biennale (2016-17), the chronicler sketches her experience of these vendors scattered in specific locations in Shanghai from the perspective of customers or passers-by. Vendors base their business on the short-lived trust of people on the move, but they have become the easiest and most effective solution for urban governance."	《51摊》（51 Tan）是一个持续性的记录项目。记录者作为第十一届上海双年展（2016-17）51人项目的参与者之一，以绘画速写勾勒出她以顾客或路人的视角体察这些散落在当时上海特定位置的摊贩。摊贩把自己的生意建立在流动中人和人的短暂信任之上，却成为城市治理下手最轻易、效果最明显的解决对象。	
51 People: The Program of the 11th Shanghai Biennale (in Chinese and English)	51人：第十一届上海双年展项目（中英双语）	Chen Yun 陈韵	First-published by China Academy of Art Press.	中国美术学院出版社出版	"This book introduces the ""51"" project from the 11th Shanghai Biennale, showcasing 51 episodes of real-life drama that touch upon various aspects of life, emotions, common sense, nature, history, economy, culture, and art, encompassing all fields"	"本书是第十一届上海双年展种的""51""项目介绍,呈现了现实人生的51出戏剧,触及生活,情感,常识,自然,历史,经济,生活,文化,艺术等所有领域。"	
Abyss Simulator	深渊模拟器	Ag	"11*16cm, 304p, July 2022. First-published by 51 Personae."	51人出版	"""Abyss Simulator"", a cyberdrama novel, a book that can produce different plot levels through interaction. It grew out of another video game of the same name, a collaborative experiment between artists Aaajiao and Ag during the pandemic in 2020. Opening this book, the reader becomes the player, and in the experience of reading-wandering-choosing, a journey of bardo without relying on begins."	《深渊模拟器》，一部赛博戏剧小说，一本能经由交互而产生不同剧情层次的书。它脱胎于另一个同名电子游戏——2020 年新冠疫情爆发期间艺术家 aaajiao 和 Ag 的一次合作实验。翻开此书，读者即成玩家，在阅读-游荡-选择的体验中，一场无所依靠的中阴之旅由此展开。	
Poetry in the Age of the Extinction Point	灭点时代的诗	Wang Wei 王炜	"14*20 cm, 270p. First-published by 51 Personae."	51人出版	"""Poetry in the Age of Vanishing Points"" often exhibit a dramatic poetic style when expressing original themes, most of them have a distinct political nature, preventing their publication and release through conventional channels. Furthermore, beyond the evident stylistic intent, the author skillfully incorporates materials from the history of recent and contemporary poetic theory, public practice, and ethnographies of non-Chinese cultures."	《灭点时代的诗》是作者的第四本诗集，这些诗在表现具有原创性的主题时，常常富有戏剧诗的风格，但由于大多具有鲜明的政治性，不能在常规渠道发表和出版，此外，除了显见的文体意志，作者还善于使用来自近、现代诗学观念史、公共实践史和非汉语民族志的素材。	
The Opposite Man	相反的人	Lu Ran 陆冉	"7*20 cm, 182p. First and second self-published in size of 100(each)."	印量/版数: 100/2 自出版	"The Opposed People is a four-panel comic series. Four-panel comics were a common form of entertainment found in newspapers and magazines, known for their light-hearted tone and popular among comic readers. Due to their relatively fixed format, they serve as both a tool and a challenge for the author. This series features three quirky and odd good friends as protagonists, utilizing the conventions of popular comics to launch a small rebellion against mundane life."	我忘了这一切是怎么开始的，只记得父亲经常对我说：‘还反了你了。’” 《相反的人》是一个四格漫画系列。四格漫画原是报刊杂志上常见的娱乐内容，基调轻松，曾为漫画读者所熟悉。因其具有相对固定的格式，对作者来说，既是工具也是挑战。此系列以三个怪模怪样的好朋友为主角，借用大众漫画体裁，向平庸的生活发起小小的反抗。	
Pom Pom became a cat.	蓬蓬变成了一只猫	Lu Ran 陆冉	"148*210 cm, 66p. First and second self-published in size of 100(each)."	印量/版数: 100/2，自出版	"The medium-length comic single volume ""Peng Peng Becomes a Cat"" tells the story of Peng Peng, a thirty-year-old girl who, trapped in the dilemma of being unable to realize her creative dreams and struggling to immerse herself in real life, transforms into a cat. As an individual, if Peng Peng had a little more courage, she might realize her dreams. However, what is most important for a cat? Beyond its narrative, the work attempts to use various forms of visual metaphors to portray the thought process."	中篇漫画单行本《蓬蓬变成了一只猫》，讲述了今年三十岁的女孩蓬蓬，在无法实现创作梦想，又难以投入现实生活的心灵困境中，变成了一只猫的故事。作为一个人，如果蓬蓬再多一点勇气，或许就会实现梦想，但对于一只猫来说，最重要的是什么呢？作品在叙事之外，尝试使用多种图像比喻形式展现思维过程。	
UNTIL2022 Old comic UNTIL2022	旧漫画	Lu Ran 陆冉	"21*29.4 cm, 92p. First-self-published in size of 500."	印量/版数: 500/1，自出版	"""旧漫画UNTIL2022"" is a personal comic zine where the author, Lu Ran, disguises themselves as different creators and takes on the roles of editor and designer. It presents 21 short comics from the years 2016 to 2022 in the format of an old magazine. Across these diverse comics, the sensitive observation of emotions, reflections on life's exploration, and experimentation with narrative forms come together to form dream-like stories."	《旧漫画UNTIL2022》是一本一个人的漫画zine，作者Lu Ran乔装成不同的创作者，并自己担任编辑和设计师，用一本旧杂志的形式呈现了2016-2022年期间的21个短篇漫画。在这些风格各异的漫画中，对情绪的敏感体察，对人生的探索反思以及对叙述形式的探索化为一个个梦境似的故事。书籍保留了手工设计过程中的痕迹，特意选择了简单的铜版纸与骑马钉，希望带来轻松惬意的阅读体验。	
Lost Magazine	Lost Magazine	Nelson Ng	17.5*24 cm. Published by volume press.	volume press出版	"It is a magazine that features real stories, personal reflections and epiphanies from people around the world. It believes that travel isn’t about fancy hotels or tourist destinations, but about immersing oneself in someplace entirely foreign to feel extremely uncomfortable so that one can learn from it. It believes that travel is a state of mind."	《LOST》是一本有關旅行和自我發現的雜誌。在這本雜誌裏，你看到的是真實的故事和來自五湖四海不同背景的人們內心深處的思考和頓悟。《LOST》堅信旅行的意義不在於華麗的酒店和名勝景點，而在於把自己徹底融入一個陌生的周遭去體會那種不適，並從中領悟。《LOST》相信，旅行是一種心態。	
BE WATER JOURNAL 3: Naturally	水象3:自然而然	Amy 爱米	"17*24 cm, 312p. April, 2021. First-published by BE WATER JOURNAL in size of 3300."	印量/版数: 3300/1，水象出版	"Be Water Journal Issue 3: Naturally, cultural creators from around the globe discuss the contemporary relationship between people and nature. 10 in-depth interviews, including: ""Eco-art practice, nature-designed architecture & community building, Amazonian underworld, aboriginal wisdom, field recordings, reflections on human self-constructed systems, synthetic biology, traditional Chinese medicine and the Eastern way, and human well-being""."	《Be Water Journal水象 》第3期：自然而然，来自全球的文化创造者，共同探讨当代人和自然的关系。10个深度访谈，包含：「生态艺术实践、自然设计建筑 & 社区营造、亚马逊地下世界、原住民智慧、田野录音、人类自建系统反思、合成生物学、中医与东方之道、人类福祉」。受访者包括：郑波、SelgasCano、Eileen Hall、品物流形、建筑大王、Henk Wildschut、孙玥、random clichés、施坦丁……	
BE WATER JOURNAL 4: Naturally Continued	水象4:自然而然 续	Amy 爱米	"17*24 cm, 312p. November, 2022. First-published by BE WATER JOURNAL in size of 2500."	印量/版数: 2500/1，水象出版	"Be Water Journal Issue 4: Naturally, Continuing, cultural creators from around the globe discuss the relationship between people and nature in contemporary times. 10 in-depth interviews including: ""Eco-Art and Design, Saami Aboriginal Architecture, African Herbal Medicine and Post-Colonialism, Ocean Soundscapes and Whale Songs, Socio-Botanicals, Young Farmers, Field Sampling, Animal Minds"", and ""The Art of Nature"". ......"""	《Be Water Journal水象 》第4期：自然而然 续，来自全球的文化创造者，共同探讨当代人和自然的关系。10个深度访谈，包含：「生态艺术与设计、萨米族原住民建筑、非洲草药与后殖民、海洋声景与鲸歌、社会植物学、青年农夫、田野采样、动物心智……」受访者包括：任日、Michele Sibiloni、徐坦、Uriel Orlow、Joar Nango、Lisa Walker、朱彦龢、编号 223……	
Legends of Beijing	北京的传说	Zichen Zhang 张紫晨，Yuenan Li 李岳南	"200p, 1982. Published by Shanghai Literature & Art Publishing House."	上海文艺出版社出版	"This book, compiled in 1980, is a bottom-up version of the legends and strange tales of the Forbidden City, as well as an oral literature version of the post-Decade Movement ""great capital of the socialist motherland"". ""It is also said to commemorate Qianlong's ability to fly at the time."""	本书编著于1980年，是自下而上关于紫禁城的传说与怪谈，也是十年运动后“社会主义祖国的伟大首都”的口头文学版聊斋。“据说，也是纪念乾隆当时能飞的事”	
Handbook for the Underworld Revolution	阴间革命手册	wei	"14.4*10.5 cm, 2020. Published by familiar path."	familiar path出版	"Released in 2020, this book is a contemporary netherworld blueprint for proletarian lone souls, a theoretical guide and program of action for crossing the fire pit. ""Lone Souls of the World Unite."""	本书发行于2020年，是无产阶级孤魂野鬼的当代阴间蓝图，过过火盆的理论指南和行动纲领。“全世界的孤魂野鬼团结起来”	
Wonder Why 1: Light	魔法文摘1：光		"11*25 cm, 68p. Published by aphakia."	无晶体出版	"There are two starting points for this series, one is to popularize knowledge of magic for the general public, and the other is to provide readings of interest to other practitioners within the magic industry. The contents of the manuscripts are mostly from the editor's usual reading materials, which are united together according to the selected topics."	本系列作品有两个出发点，一方面是面向公众普及魔法知识，另一方面是为魔法行业内其他从业者提供兴趣读物。稿件内容多来自于编辑平时的阅读材料，根据选题统编在一起。	
Wonder Why 2: Form	魔法文摘2：形·体		"11*25 cm, 68p. Published by aphakia."	无晶体出版	"There are two starting points for this series, one is to popularize knowledge of magic for the general public, and the other is to provide readings of interest to other practitioners within the magic industry. The contents of the manuscripts are mostly from the editor's usual reading materials, which are united together according to the selected topics."	本系列作品有两个出发点，一方面是面向公众普及魔法知识，另一方面是为魔法行业内其他从业者提供兴趣读物。稿件内容多来自于编辑平时的阅读材料，根据选题统编在一起。	
Wonder Why 3: Luminous Beings	魔法文摘3：引力线		"11*25 cm, 68p. Published by aphakia."	无晶体出版	"There are two starting points for this series, one is to popularize knowledge of magic for the general public, and the other is to provide readings of interest to other practitioners within the magic industry. The contents of the manuscripts are mostly from the editor's usual reading materials, which are united together according to the selected topics."	本系列作品有两个出发点，一方面是面向公众普及魔法知识，另一方面是为魔法行业内其他从业者提供兴趣读物。稿件内容多来自于编辑平时的阅读材料，根据选题统编在一起。	
Wonder Why 4: Cocoon	魔法文摘4：茧		"11*25 cm, 68p. Published by aphakia."	无晶体出版	"There are two starting points for this series, one is to popularize knowledge of magic for the general public, and the other is to provide readings of interest to other practitioners within the magic industry. The contents of the manuscripts are mostly from the editor's usual reading materials, which are united together according to the selected topics."	本系列作品有两个出发点，一方面是面向公众普及魔法知识，另一方面是为魔法行业内其他从业者提供兴趣读物。稿件内容多来自于编辑平时的阅读材料，根据选题统编在一起。	
Catalog: Tactile Communications from Analog to Digital	触 Catalog		2022. Published by Icosa Magazine.	二十面体出版	"This book is a compilation of a wide range of materials related to haptic art, presenting nearly thirty sub-topics related to haptics, from perception, cinema, materials, architecture, and design, to contact improvisation, bondage, data visualization, and programming with the body."	本书整理了非常多跟触觉艺术相关的素材，呈现了跟触觉相关的从感知、电影、材料、建筑、设计，到接触即兴、绳缚、数据可触化、⽤⾝体编程等将近三⼗个⼦话题。	
Shadow of the Sugar House	糖舍熵影	Liu Chuanhong 刘传宏	16.5*22.5cm. First-published by Jiangsu Phoenix Literature and Art Publishing in size of 1200.	印量/版数: 1200/1，江苏凤凰文艺出版社出版	"The designers used candy as a medium to blend the story of the sugar factory's history, the artist's thematic work and the contemporary results of the remodeling by the two architects. The designers were given a lollipop machine from the same period as the building, and it was a great idea to restore the machine and call on a team to make the candy, giving each reader a candy bar. The process of restoring the machine and boiling the candies meets the reader in a small booklet, a book that has a sweet taste in time."	设计师以糖为媒介，将糖厂历史故事、艺术家主题作品与当代两位建筑师改造成果融为一体。设计师获得一台与建筑同时期的棒棒糖机，设计师修复机器，号召团队熬制糖果，为每一位读者赠送一枚糖果是个不错的主意。修复机器、熬制糖果的过程以小别册的方式与读者见面，这是一本在时光中有甜蜜味觉的书。	
Products by Psychic Records	神棍唱片出品物 (唤醒巴特西、上海现场、大平原：四个时刻等）	Psychic Records神棍唱片	Various Format. Published by Psychic Records.	神棍唱片出版	"Founded in 2019, PSYCHIC is devoted to unearthing, organizing, and publishing out-of-print and unissued musical works connected to the early 21st century Chinese avant-garde, including experimental and non-mainstream music"	神棍厂牌成立于2019年 致力于本世纪初中国前卫、实验、另类音乐之绝版作品再版及未公开发表作品的挖掘整理出版。	
Che Pi	扯皮	Zuoxiao Zuzhou/Sun Xiaoxi 左小祖咒/孙晓曦	"10.5*15 cm,1028p, Aug 2017. First-published in size 0f 1000."	印数/版数1000/1，自出版	"is an interview collection with musician ZuoXiao ZuZhou, covering a decade and totaling 1028 pages. The book emphasizes pure text, presented in a straightforward manner, with no barriers between the content and the reader. Each page alternates between a question and an answer, capturing the essence of Zuo's unique voice, both in discourse and music. The varied text size mimics the nuances of speech. Interestingly, the book is wrapped in a text-filled sheet that readers must tear off before starting, alluding to the title ""扯皮"" (meaning ""Tearing Off""). This design choice doubles as self-mockery, suggesting that the author's preface, and even the content, is up for reader discretion."	《扯皮》是音乐家左小祖咒的访谈集。内容跨度达10年，厚达1028页，体现言论的体量。本书中，文本（言论）占绝对统治地位，因此我用单纯直接甚至有点粗暴的方式展现文本，它和读者之间没有任何障碍。结构上，一页一问、一页一答，既可只看问题，也可只看回答。文字的编排在固定范围内有大有小，因为声音的强弱与大小即言论表达的特征。看似随意的字距是某种“走调”，但这正是祖咒和他音乐的特点。书被一张布满文字的纸包裹，阅读前需要先将纸扯掉，一个是呼应了书名《扯皮》，也是一种自嘲——作者的自序是可以被扔掉的——你可以不相信这里面的任何话。	
Do It: 2021	做：中国2021	Hans Ulrich Obrist/Cao Dan/Xiaoxi Sun 汉斯-乌尔里希·奥布里斯特/曹丹/孙晓曦	"19.5*27 cm,460p, 2021. First-published by Zhongxin Publishing Group."	中信出版社	"co-curated by Hans Ulrich Obrist and Cao Dan, showcases 108 contemporary Chinese artists. Embracing China's ancient binding and Xuan paper, artists' names are alphabetically displayed on the fore-edge, serving as a visual index. While interior layouts vary, there's an overall cohesion. The cloth-bound cover with an embossed title, combined with its 400 pages and 6cm thickness, delivers a ceremonial browsing experience. Contrasting fonts differentiate text, with orange and black highlighting Chinese and English content. Echoing the series' signature orange, the book isn't just a collection but an embodiment of contemporary Chinese art."""	《做：中国2021》（do it – China 2021）是策展人Hans Ulrich Obrist和Cao Dan共同策划的项目出版物，其中收录了108位当代华裔艺术家的方案。书籍设计采用了中国传统的古线装，纸张采用宣纸，艺术家的名字以姓氏字母的顺序印在筒子页的书口上，形成了强烈的视觉索引。内页版式根据不同艺术家的方案，产生了灵活多变的图文关系，但又保持了整体性。封面采用布料，书名烫黑。全书采用了不常规的长方形开本，多达400多页，厚达6厘米，使得读者翻阅的方式更有仪式感。整本书使用衬线和无衬线两种字体形成反差，在内文中用橙色和黑色区分了中英两语。全书延续了《Do it》的标志性橙色，整本书犹如雕塑一般，强有力的表达了中国当代艺术的影响力，书籍本身就像一件当代艺术作品。	
NYC FISHING JOURNAL	纽约钓鱼日志	YI XIN TONG 童义欣	"Overall dimensions variable, 2019. Published by Gong Press."	弓出版出版	"The book offers a glimpse into the author's fishing trips through the city through more than 200 photographs, three page-turning video stills, and other related objects. The photographs are printed in various sizes, loosely tied with fishing line, labeled, and arranged according to the author's organizing habits."	本书通过 200 多张图片、3 本翻页视频剧照和其他相关物件，让人们得以一窥作者在这座城市的钓鱼之旅。照片被打印成各种尺寸，用鱼线松散地捆绑，贴上标签，并按照作者的整理习惯进行排列。	
ENVIRONMENTAL LOVE MANUAL	恋爱环保手册	YI XIN TONG 童义欣	"24.5*14.8 cm, 180p, 2021. Published by Palais de Tokyo."	巴黎东京宫出版	"This book, a bilingual collection of seventy-two poems in French and Chinese, created with the support of the Cai Guanshen Foundation Contemporary Art Award and the Palais de Tokyo, contemplates the ways in which the mind and body of the individual and nature intermingle, as well as the ways in which the respective internal contradictions of romantic relationships and environmental endeavors serve as metaphors for each other."	本书是由蔡冠深基金会当代艺术奖和东京宫支持创作的一部由七十二首诗组成的中法双语诗集，思考个人与自然的身心交融，以及浪漫关系和环保努力的各自内部矛盾互为隐喻的方式。	
	完美的流线型的物体上平坦的疤痕	Mei Si Yu 梅思羽	Self-published.	自出版	"This is one of those books that was lucky to have a reader before it was made into a book, and consists mostly of reading traces. It offers some experience and contains a story besides. Unfortunately, it cannot provide knowledge."	这是一本在被制成书前就拥有读者的幸运的书，并且主要由阅读痕迹构成。它提供一些经验，除此之外还包含一个故事。遗憾的是，它无法提供知识。	
Language Paste	语言膏	Ding Cheng丁成	"336p, Oct 2019. Published by Showwe Information."	秀威資訊出版	"This book is a selected collection of poems by Ding Cheng, written between June 2013 and March 2019. It is also a concentrated presentation of his ongoing exploration and experimentation with Chinese poetry, showcasing his latest achievements."	本書是丁成於2013年6月至2019年3月之間創作的詩歌精選集，也是他對漢語詩歌持續探索、實驗的最新成果的集中呈現。	
In Search of Tashui Village: A Guide	寻找踏水村指南	Zhi Shen 沈至	"14*20.3 cm, 112p. August, 2023. First-published by Jiangsu Phoenix Literature and Art Publishing in size of 500."	印数/版数 500/1 江苏凤凰文艺出版社出版	"In Search of Tashui Village: A Guide is the debut poetry collection of the young poet Shen Zhi. It serves as a comprehensive display of his poetic spirit in the Chinese realm. The book comprises a series of poems titled ""Guide"". From ""Insomnia"" to ""Screen"", from ""Tashui Village"" to ""Oxford"", the ""Guide Poems"" series delicately examines urban experiences marked by distinctive era traits and the dispersed insights under the context of globalization with a tender post-modern gaze, rich in personal experiences.Shen Zhi's philosophical training has honed the intellectual depth of his poems. His works, starting from subtle realizations in daily life, travel through the maze of logic or the prism of language to reach the domain of the ""unspeakable"", as referred to by Wittgenstein"	《寻找踏水村指南》是青年诗人沈至的首部诗歌作品集，也是他在汉语领域内对其“诗心”的一次集中展演。全书包合以“指南”为题的系列诗歌。从“失眠”到“屏幕”，从“踏水村”到“牛津”，“指南诗”系列以柔软的后现代目光搓捻那些有着显著时代特征的城市经验及全球化语境下的离散体悟，充满个人体验。沈至所受的哲学训练研磨了他诗歌的智性底色，他的作品从生活中的微小体悟出发，经逻辑的迷言或语言的虹管抵达维特根斯坦所称“不可言说”的领域。	
Cold Hearted	绝情种	Jialu Chen 陈嘉璐	"120pp 4/4 color offset, 40pp 1/1 color offset. June, 2022. Self-published first edition of 300, Guangzhou."	"印量/版数: 300/1，自出版, 广州"	"The publication has two parts, including a short novel about the gathering or separation of women in different time and space in the Pearl River Delta from 1920s to 2020, as well as a photographic record of the author tracing the traces of the Gupo(comb sister) and the Gupouk (comb sisters’ houses) . The text and photography are two alternating routes, they flowed east and south along the Xijiang waters to Southeast Asia. This book is one of the publication plans of ""Gupouk Trilogy""."	本书有两个部分，包含一篇讲述1920年代至2020年，珠三角地区不同时空的女性流动过程中相聚或离散的短篇小说，以及作者追寻姑婆足跡和姑婆屋的摄影记录。文本和攝影是两条互相交错的路线，他们沿着西江水域向东南方向流动，直至东南亚。本书为“姑婆屋三部曲”出版计划之一。	
A Manual of Khoomei	呼麦练习指南	Xiaoqing Zhu 朱晓晴	"Self-published, 2022."	自出版	The author of this book is an amateur Khoomei practitioner who has learned and summarized some theoretical and practical knowledge about Khoomei in recent years through apprenticeship and self-study. The content of this book combines the key theories of Khoomei-related works and the author's personal experience in the process of practicing Khoomei as a scaffold to create her own singing style.	本书作者是一名业余呼麦练习者，近年来通过拜师和自学的方式了解和总结了一些关于呼麦的理论和实践知识。本书在内容上结合了呼麦相关著作的关键理论和作者练习过程中的个人体会，以此为脚手架来创造属于自己的演唱方式和风格。	
Quadrant Island	象限岛	An De 安德	"22*12cm, 1/200, Chinese, Self-Published"	22*12 cm，印数200，简体中文，自出版	"""Quadrant Island"" is from ""Blue Valley Poetry Collection: Volume One"". Ande, Huang Hao, Shi Si (Fourteen), Hou Jiachuan, Long Xiaoyang... A group of young poets active in Chengdu formed a loose poetry organization called ""Blue Valley"" over drinks. In 2018, they compiled their works and self-published the ""Blue Valley Poetry Collection""."	《象限岛》出自《蓝谷地诗丛·第一辑》。安德，黄浩，十四，侯佳川，龙小羊……活跃在成都的一帮青年诗人以酒为媒，自发形成松散诗歌组织“蓝谷地”，于2018年汇篇成集，自印《蓝谷地诗丛》。	
Off-Season Lectures: An Anthology to Water (2021-2022)	淡季讲座：致水自选集（2021-2022）	Zhi Shu 致水	"67p, Jun 2023. First-published by ϔ"	ϔ出版	"""「淡季讲座」"" is a collection of poems dedicated to Water 2022. This compilation will continue the themes of ""「幽灵学」"" and ""Survival and Nostalgia."""	「淡季讲座」是致水2022年的诗歌合集，本辑将延续「幽灵学」和「幸存与怀旧」的主题。	
Chán Magazine Issue 01	馋Chán 第一期	"Dot Zhihan Jia, Jiaying Kou 贾芷涵，寇佳瑛"	17*24 cm. 2021. First-published by Chán Magazine x Good Company Intl. Chinese and English. First edition 200 copy Self-published	17*24cm 印数/版数 1/200，Chán Magazine 和 In Good Company Intl.出版	"The first issue of Chán seeks to explore the interconnections between individual experience and collective identities through food - essays, illustrations, images, poetries that construct lines of difference weaved together by memories of food."	第一期《馋Chán》旨在通过食物探索个人经历与集体身份之间的相互联系--文章、插图、图片和诗歌构建了由食物记忆编织而成的差异线。	
We're Caught Between Two Winds: The Island Guerrilla Relay Co-Writes	我们被夹在两道风里：海岛游击接力共写	lava lake	"13*21 cm, Jun 2023. First-published by PukouFactory in size of 100."	100/1，浦口工厂出版	"Island Writing Co-Creation is a collaborative effort between the Lava Lake-Hainan Group and the Hainan artist community. Through the relay of communication, the ramblings of words, and the tidal back-and-forth movement of understanding, the image of the island is resurrected. We are pulled by escapism on one hand and struck by the vibrations of ""reefing"" on the other. Between the two winds full of messages, there are engraved body tracks, cognitive ghosts, and the waveform of friendship."	海岛游击接力写由lava lake-海南小组与海南艺术家社群共笔完成。在接力式的交流，絮絮的言说，潮汐式往复的理解运动中，复活了海岛的映像。我们一面被逃逸癖牵引，一面又被“触礁”的震动夹击着。两道蕴满信息的风里，镶嵌着身体的轨迹、认知的幽灵和友谊的波形。	
Sin and Love	罪与爱	Jin Te 金特	"13*18 cm, 294p. First-published by Copy Creation."	副本制作出版	"The direct purpose of writing ""Guilt and Love"" is to express my own views on ""blind faith in material construction."" I believe such an approach is inappropriate. Material development is necessary, but to prioritize it above all else is unsuitable. I also believe that the reasons for reaching this point are complex. The explanations given in books and on the internet are superficial and unsatisfying. Therefore, I wanted to write a novel to explore these matters further."	写《罪与爱》的直接目的，就在于对“迷信物质建设”表达一下我自己的看法，我认为这样做是不妥当的，认为，物质建设是必要，以物质建设为尊就不合适了，还认为，之所以走到这一步，原因是很复杂的，书上网络上给出的解释又皮疼肉不疼，于是就想写部小说探索一下。	
The Three Impossible Routines.	三种不可能的日常	Li Yao 黎幺	"12*18 cm, May 2023. First-published in size of 150 editions by Flying Elephant."	印量/版数: 150/1，飞象界出版	"This is a book that aims to explore the ""everyday"". The everyday in this book is an everyday that is divided and deformed through association. The author hopes that these ""divisions"" and ""deformations"" will not jeopardize the integrity and dignity of the everyday. Imagination, by virtue of its crystalline nature, reflects the everyday on different prisms and breaks it down into a number of words that can be easily grasped and enriched by language."	这是一本旨在探讨“日常”的书。这本书中的日常，是一个通过联想，被分化与变形的日常。作者希望这些“分化”与“变形”能够无损于日常的完整和尊严。想象凭借它的晶体特性，将日常反射在不同的棱面上，将其拆析成为许多个易于把握、易于用语言充实的词汇。	
The Possibilities and Impossibilities of Art Archives (Repositories).	艺术档案（库）的可能与不可能	51人 51 Personae	"12.5*17.5 cm, 440p, Aug 2023. First-published by Kali Books and The Phantom Archives."	迦梨图书+ 虚无乡档案出版	"The purpose of this book is to address the gaps in existing literature concerning research, juxtaposition, and focused discussions on Asian art archives. This book provides an opportunity for Asia's archival repositories and individuals involved in archival work to acquaint themselves with one another, understand what their peers in the field are engaged in, how they go about it, and what more can be accomplished collectively."	本书旨在填补现有文献中关于亚洲艺术档案的研究、并置和集中讨论的空白。本书为亚洲的档案库和围绕档案工作的人们提供了一个机会，让他们互相认识，了解档案工作的同行正在做什么，他们如何做，以及他们还有什么可以做。	
One Man's Poetry: A Modern Translation of the Book of Psalms.	一个人的诗：诗经今译	Zhu Fa 朱琺	14.8*21 cm. First-published by Anti-gravity Organization Wang Er Xiao Soy Sauce Shop in size 0f 128.	印数/版数 128/1，反重力組織王二小醬油舖出版	"One Man's Poetry: A Modern Translation of Shih-ching, launched in 2011 by Zhufà, is a set of modern poems that aims to render three hundred works from Shih (i.e., Book of Songs), the earliest collection of Chinese poetry. Three volumes of Zhou Nan, Shao Nan, Bei Feng have been edited, printed and published by himself. Zhufà is willing to redefine Shih in his own voice through contemporary interpretation. The translation of poetry from the oldest to the newest highlights the history and richness of the Chinese language."	《一個人的《詩》：詩經今譯》自二一一年起啟動，是旨在依次呈現最早的漢語詩集《詩》（即《詩經》）三百首作品的現代詩集。朱琺「一個人」自結集自排印，已印行《周南》《召南》《邶風》三冊，作者願以個人名義重新定義《詩》經「今譯」即詩歌翻譯，通過「漢譯漢」，將最古老的詩翻轉成爲最新的詩。	
"Air, Skin and Water."	空气、皮肤和水	Wan Xia 万夏	"14*19 cm, 2023. First-published by BEIJING ZITO BOOKS in size of 300."	印数/版数 300/1，北京紫图图书公司出版	A 25-year-old's perception of the world in 1987.	1987年，一个25岁的年轻人对世界的感知。	
"The Lonely, Beautiful Garden"	孤寂美丽的花园	Wan Xia 万夏	"14*19 cm, 2023. First-published by BEIJING ZITO BOOKS in size of 300."	印数/版数 300/1，北京紫图图书公司出版	"Poetry notes written during five ridiculous and insane quarantines back in China during the three-year epidemic, from 2020 to 2022."	从2020年到2022年，三年疫情期间，回中国的5次荒唐且疯狂的隔离期间写下的诗歌笔记。	
I Thought I Was Shedding Tears of Sorrow	我以为流下了悲伤的泪水	Wan Xia 万夏	"14*19 cm, 2023. First-published by BEIJING ZITO BOOKS in size of 300."	印数/版数 300/1，北京紫图图书公司出版	"Documenting deep feelings from 2019 to March 2020, from the revolution of the times in Hong Kong to the early days of the epidemic in China."	记录从2019年到2020年3月，从香港的时代革命到中国疫情初期的深切感受。	
Ignoramus	低人一等集	anusman 王烁	Published by aquamanile books.	aquamanile books出版	"Wang Shuo is an amateur cartoonist, cartoon critic, and the first person to study independent cartooning in China. After graduating from Tsinghua University, majoring in printmaking, he studied in France for five years and received a master's degree in cartooning from the Institut Européen d'Images in Angoulême, France, during which time he published Anusman's Silent Comics 1&2. After returning to China, he taught at the Central Academy of Fine Arts and received a doctorate degree, and authored the comic book textbook Comics Lesson: New Language of Comics."	王烁(anusman)是一名业余漫画家、漫画评论者、国内第一个研究独立漫画的人。清华大学美术学院版画专业毕业后赴法国留学五年，获法国安古兰欧洲图像学院漫画硕士，期间出版《anusman的无字漫画1&2》。回国后于中央美术学院教书，并获得博士学位，并著有漫画教材《漫画课：漫画新语》。	
Carpe Diem	及时行乐	Luo Yang 罗洋	"19*24 cm, 96p, 2022. Published by La Maison de Z."	La Maison de Z出版	"The author of this book, Luo Yang, has photographed more than a hundred girls over the past ten years, observing and capturing their delicate transition from adolescence to adulthood. At the same time, the photographer projects her own evolution into the models to capture and respond to their emotional changes as young women."	本书作者罗洋在过去的⼗年里跟随拍摄了⼀百多名⼥孩，观察并抓取她们从青春期到成年的微妙过渡。与此同时，摄影师将自己的成长演变投射进对模特的拍摄当中，以捕捉和回应她们作为年轻⼥性的情感变化。	
Prison Art issue 1-6	狱望杂志1-6期	Shenghua Wang 王胜华	130p. Published by Prison Art.	狱望杂志出版	"The series of publications center around the theme of ""Art Intervention in Prisons,"" collecting a variety of cases and related materials that employ artistic means to impact inmates. Beyond this, diverse forms of art have found their way into prisons, each yielding a plethora of creations through distinct avenues. The chief editor aims to draw attention to the endeavors and efforts of art intervention in this realm through the compilation of such works and their subsequent publication and distribution, fostering greater awareness among a wider audience."	本书以“艺术介入监狱”为主题，收集了各种通过艺术手段来影响犯人的案例和相关资料。除此之外，多种艺术形式也都以各自不同的方式介入到监狱，并产出了不少作品。主编希望通过这些收集工作和出版物发行，让更多的人来关注艺术介入这个领域的尝试和努力。	
	潮州妖精鬼神故事	Yulin Qiu 丘玉麟	2022. Published by On Kino.	论电影院出版	"After the establishment of the P.R. China, although legends of spirits and ghosts continued to circulate throughout the country, gradually, there were no new supernatural beings emerging. Eventually, even the pre-liberation era spirits and creatures gradually became less active. In the mid-1920s, a young man Yulin Qiu, from Guangdong, went on a journey to Beijing to pursue his education at Yanjing University. It was during this period that Zhou Zuoren initiated the Folk Literature Renaissance Movement, an endeavor that deeply resonated with Yulin Qiu. Filled with inspiration, he eventually returned to his hometown of Chaozhou. Back in Chaozhou, Qiu embarked on a mission to the local community, compelling them to gather stories centering around the region's mythical creatures, spirits, and deities. These captivating tales were meticulously compiled and, in 1930, saw the light of day in the form of a comprehensive volume titled ""Tales of Ghosts, Goblins, and Gods of Chaozhou."" However, the passage of three decades would usher in a dark period in the book's history, as it became a casualty of the ""Four Olds"" movement, subsequently being removed from publication and consigned to oblivion. Remarkably, in recent years, this remarkable collection of stories has remained conspicuously absent from discussions and publications focusing on Chaoshan folklore. Fortunately, a unique copy of ""Chaozhou Spirits and Ghost Stories"" was preserved and reprinted in 2022 by On Kino. This book documents the tales of spirits and mysteries from the Chaozhou region. What's astonishing is that after more than 60 years, these stories of Chaozhou spirits and supernatural beings are once again meeting a new generation of readers through printed media, preserving this important cultural heritage."	解放后，还是有妖精鬼怪在中国大地上四处游荡与出没的。渐渐的，就没有新妖新精，最后，解放前的妖精也不许出来了。 一九二零年代中期，广东青年丘玉麟前往北京，入读燕京大学。适逢周作人发动民间文艺复兴运动，丘玉麟受到了感召，回到家乡潮州，发动了当地人采编了大量当地妖精鬼神故事，于1930年结册出版《潮州妖精鬼神故事》。又过了30年，时逢“破四旧”运动，该书被历史除名、销毁。近年来出版的关于潮汕民间文学的出版物中也不见对该书的提及、论述。 论电影院幸藏《潮州妖精鬼神故事》孤本一册，于2022年影印再版。潮州的妖精鬼神们想不到，又过了60年之后，竟又能通过纸质媒介与新读者们见面。	
1413 Magazine issue 7: Wellness	养生	"featuring: Shuhua Xiong, Ramona Wang, Jacob Jesse Perez, Murrie Rosenfeld, LB3, Zhang Yue, Weiyi Li, Xiaohang Qiu, Meiting Song, Jimbo Tan..."	"24*31.5 cm, 153p. Self-published."	自出版	"When typing: Why Chinese___ in Google, the first thing that pops up is Why Chinese drink hot water. It is the ultimate cure to every single minor ailment and pain. Why? Why do we love love drinking hot water? Hoping to answer such questions, here comes our new issue #WELLNESS"	在谷歌输入Why Chinese 弹出的相关词条，第一条就是Why Chinese Drink Hot Water。不知不觉，多喝热水像是中国神秘绝招解决着各式各样的小病疼痛。那么，到底Why Chinese Drink Hot Water?带着这样的疑惑，第七期1413依旧是摸索着大家养生的脚步，换个角度看看大家是如何养生的。	
"""There's a Way Tomorrow"" - A Bunch of Work Files with Steps in Progress"	「明天就有辦法」—— 一沓彳亍以行的工作档案	Shen Jun & Li Jizhong 沈军&李继忠	"6.7*37.5 cm, 15.5*29.7 cm, 14.3*21 cm, 172p + 1p(A1), 2021. First-published by StepBackForward."	彳亍以行出版	"""Things will Work Out Tomorrow A Growing Collection of StepBackForward Methodologies"" is the publication of StepBackForward.art's first phase. We regard this book as a timely sample report of the emerging art scene in Hong Kong, different artists can be linked through keywords, corresponding to their working methods, in the hope of inspiring readers."	《「明天就有辦法」 — 一沓彳亍以行的工作檔案》是StepBackForward.art第一階段的出版物。我們將這本書視為一份香港新興藝術界適時的樣本報告，不同的藝術家可透過關鍵詞而連結，對應藝術家的工作方法，以期對讀者有所啟發。	
Tokyo·Feng Li	东京·冯立	Feng Li 冯立	"30*22 cm, 46p, 2023. Published by Place M."	Place M出版	"This book contains 46 photographs that are still very much in Feng Li's personal style - even though he was shooting on the streets of Tokyo for the first time. From a drunk in a flashbulb to a portrait of a cigarette smoker on Moriyama Avenue, from a cemetery in central Tokyo to Cai Guo-Qiang's fireworks, Feng Li uses his photography to engage with his predecessors as a photographer in Japan across time and space."	本书收录了46张依旧极具冯立个人风格的摄影作品———即使他是第一次在东京的街头进行拍摄。从闪光灯下的醉汉到森山大道抽烟的肖像，从东京市中心的墓地到蔡国强的烟花，冯立用自己的摄影和日本的摄影家前辈们进行着跨时空的切磋。	
My Funny Valentine (Cassette Edition)	爱对了人情人节每天都过（卡带版）	Shang Liang 商量	"10.8*7.2*1.6 cm, 76p, 2022. Self-published in size of 500 editions."	自出版	"144 photographs of strange couples taken on the street and the 12 love songs that were the biggest hits thirty years ago, echo and loop each other throughout the book, like a self-made album of love songs ripped on tape, trying to show the passion and despair, sweetness and bitterness of contemporary love while preserving the fascination and imagination of the late last century."	144 张拍摄于街头的陌生情侣日常照片与 12 首三十多年前都曾红极一时的情歌对唱金曲，在书中交相呼应并循环往复，如同一盘用磁带翻录的自制情歌合辑，在保留对上个世纪末的迷恋与想象的同时，试图展现当代爱情中的激情与落寞、甜蜜与苦涩。	